

AINSLEY HAREWOOD

Digital Project Manager & Frontend developer

CONTACT

+868 733-2433

harewoodestate@gmail.com

Trinidad & Tobago

SKILLS

PROFESSIONAL

- Language Agnostic (C Based)
- o HTML5
- JavaScript ES6
- o CSS3/PostCSS
- o Agile Project Management

EDUCATION

O BSC. COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Hertfordshire

2005-2008

HOBBIES

Socialising with friends and family, looking at documentaries, and learning new technologies

ABOUT ME

I'm a high energy achiever that has been working in the digital world for over 12 years as a developer and project manager. My experience is diverse as I operated in leadership roles in both product based and service based environments. I've developed my own learning strategy that allows me to add value to any operation in minimal time.

EXPERIENCE

FRONTEND DEVELOPER | 2021 - Prsent

Klove & Sitch Agency, Trinidad & Tobago

Created design and development workflow processes to allow multiple resources to seamlessly work together on projects without bottlenecks.

Lead the creation of the ONE brand, inclusive of logo, packaging, colors etc, which is a new unreleased FMCG product. This product isn't launched yet but the microsite can be seen here.

Lead the creation of the ONE brand main website. This

• product hasn't been launched yet but the main site can be seen here.

Lead the creation of Klove & Sitch agency's main website. I managed the design process with the designer to come

 up with the look and feel and created the frontend from scratch from Figma design files. This was built on the GatsbyJs framework. (https://kloveandsitch.agency)

Created workflow for team with Jira, Toggl and GIT based on

 best practices for consistent codebase and continuous integration.

TECHNOLOGY OFFICER I 2017 - 2021

Pastryland Bakery, Trinidad & Tobago

I developed and codified all operating processes as well as integrated technology into the business model for ease of management.

- Designed the layout for three cafe locations in Sketchup
 - Selected market ready SaaS tools to be used for simplifying
- operational processes and installed and configured them across all cafes



AINSLEY HAREWOOD

Digital Project Manager & Frontend developer

LINKS

- ONE Microsite (not launched)
- DSB Main Site (not launched)

- 🧬 🛮 Planning.gov.tt (archived)
- Ø Official T&T Website (Drupal)

EXPERIENCE

- Pastryland Bakery, Trinidad & Tobago
 - Created documentation and trained all employees on the use of software.
 - Negotiated deals with Nestle Caribbean for better pricing on their FMCG in the cafes
 - Negotiated financing with financial institutions
 - Negotiated financing with the Government of Trinidad & Tobago during the pandemic.

PRODUCT MANAGER I 2014 - 2016

F1RST Media, Trinidad & Tobago

Jr Product Manager of the F1RST app which was the first of its kind in Trinidad & Tobago, Barbados and Jamaica.

- Implemented SEO best practices to optimize frontend code for
- F1RST.com which increased traffic to the website significantly resulting in a steady incline in conversions.
 - Carried out User Acceptance testing for F1RST.com and mobile
- apps and created tasks in Pivotal Tracker for developers to complete.
- Created frontend landing pages for F1RST.com

Government of the Republic of Trinidad & Tobago

- Created development practices for the entire IT department which allowed development to be streamlined.
- Sole developer of the Ministry of Planning's main website.
 - Sole developer of the main events website for the 50th
- Independence of Trinidad and Tobago. This website is still featured on Drupal.org